<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colorado Springs Real Estate Video Blog with Jeff Ryder</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Ryder Team is to be your best resource for Colorado Springs real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Ryder Team, your professional Colorado Springs Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 10:03:12 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 10:03:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Our Team Is the Best Choice in Colorado Springs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_BoXAxMRVLY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to take a moment to answer a question I hear a lot. “There are almost 5,000 real estate agents in Colorado Springs. Why should I hire your team?” This is a really good question, so I want to give you a few really good answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your Colorado Springs home? Get a home value report
Buying a Colorado Springs Home? Click here for full MLS access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason you should hire our team is because of our experience. I’ve been involved in the sale of over 1,200 homes in the past 16 years and during this time, the real estate market has changed a lot. Prices and sales went from extreme highs to extreme lows and back again. When the market changes, we change with it to help our clients navigate the challenges they face when purchasing or selling a home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t do it alone, however. To really get great results for our clients, it takes a whole team. We have a great one. When you hire us, you get a team of professionals working for you for the price of one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great reason to hire us is because of our flexible and innovative programs designed to maximize the equity in your home. For example, our common sense listing program offers flexible commissions, the right to sell your house yourself and pay nothing, and the right to fire us at any time if you aren’t happy. You can even list your house with us for a dollar with our “dollar listing plan,” when you move up to a new home. These are just a few of our innovative programs created with our clients’ best interest in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WE’VE SEEN EVERYTHING THAT THE REAL ESTATE MARKET HAS TO OFFER.%20http://localhost:4000/why-our-team-is-best-choice-in-colorado.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WE’VE SEEN EVERYTHING THAT THE REAL ESTATE MARKET HAS TO OFFER.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you should hire us because of the team behind our team. Keller Williams is the largest real estate company in the world for the number of agents and the number of homes sold. Their technology, training, and resources are unmatched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home or know somebody who is, remember that our experience, our flexible and creative programs, and our company and team-wide support is what we have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or want to learn more, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email today. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 10:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-our-team-is-best-choice-in-colorado.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-our-team-is-best-choice-in-colorado.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What 4 Lessons Did We Learn From the 2007 Housing Crisis?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tV-YhRRZHCw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today in Colorado Springs, many of our local communities are seeing home prices that are even higher than what we observed during the 2007 housing crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That period of our market may have been difficult, but it also taught us some important lessons. Today I’d like to share four of the most important things we learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t buy a home you can’t afford.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people during, and just prior to, the housing crisis in 2007 bought properties beyond their budget out of fear. They worried that, if they didn’t make a move, they would be priced out of the market and lose out on ever having the opportunity to purchase a home again. In retrospect, we know that this way of thinking is fatally flawed. So don’t buy into the hype. If you cannot afford a home now, it doesn’t mean you never will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Don’t always believe your home will go up in value.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of people in our market falsely assume that home prices will always increase. Yet this is not the case. The reality is that prices fluctuate. Real estate purchases are best thought of as a long-term commitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure you have adequate reserves.&lt;/strong&gt; During the housing crisis, homeowners without sufficient savings found themselves in an extremely difficult position. Experts say that you should have at least six months’ worth of reserves so that you can sustain your lifestyle in the event of major unforeseen expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=IF YOU CANNOT AFFORD A HOME NOW, IT DOESN’T MEAN YOU NEVER WILL BE ABLE TO.%20http://localhost:4000/what-4-lessons-did-we-learn-from-2007.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“IF YOU CANNOT AFFORD A HOME NOW, IT DOESN’T MEAN YOU NEVER WILL BE ABLE TO.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Submit a big, healthy down payment when buying.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people today are putting down as little as possible, but this is not the ideal way to proceed. If a downturn in prices pushes homeowners like these to sell, they are sure to encounter financial hardship as a result. Submitting the largest down payment you can afford will make your home more affordable on a monthly basis and will make it easier to hold onto your property during turbulent times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-4-lessons-did-we-learn-from-2007.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-4-lessons-did-we-learn-from-2007.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to prepare for a home inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/H-3-KqO9E0Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you’ve decided to sell your home and, before you know it, it goes under contract. Before the deal can close, though, you’ve got to pass a home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home inspection contingency is present in most real estate contracts to allow the buyer to back out should any major issues become apparent. It’s at this stage that many deals fall through. So, with so much at stake, it just makes sense to thoroughly prepare your property in advance. Making these preparations will save you a lot of negotiation and repair work down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=PREPARING YOUR PROPERTY BEFORE IT’S INSPECTED WILL SAVE YOU A LOT OF NEGOTIATION AND REPAIR WORK DOWN THE ROAD.%20http://localhost:4000/5-problems-frequently-found-by-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“PREPARING YOUR PROPERTY BEFORE IT’S INSPECTED WILL SAVE YOU A LOT OF NEGOTIATION AND REPAIR WORK DOWN THE ROAD.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following areas are where unpleasant surprises often arise and, ultimately, either kill the sale or cost the seller a lot of money:
&lt;strong&gt;1. The roof.&lt;/strong&gt; Repairs to the roof can be very expensive. If you think your home may need a new roof, consider taking care of it before listing your property on the market. With all the hail damage we get in our area, these repairs might be covered by your insurance.
&lt;strong&gt;2. The heating and cooling system.&lt;/strong&gt; Regardless of the season, a home inspector will want to make sure the heating and cooling systems are in good shape. I highly advise hiring a professional prior to your inspection to uncover any issues beforehand.
&lt;strong&gt;3. Electrical issues.&lt;/strong&gt; Making sure your electrical systems are up-to-code before the inspection is critical because electrical violations are both common and easy to spot. Also, faulty wiring is a fire hazard. The sooner you address these issues, the safer your home will be.
&lt;strong&gt;4. The plumbing.&lt;/strong&gt; Plumbing problems can cause your deal to go down the drain. So, never put these issues off.
&lt;strong&gt;5. Water damage.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if you don’t have an active leak, stains on ceilings are often signs of previous problems. Though this past issue may have been as harmless as an overflowing toilet, buyers will suspect the worst if they see signs of water damage. Always fix any current leaks in your home and cover signs of previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you plan on selling your home, you may want to consider having a pre-inspection performed. This can help uncover any of the issues we’ve discussed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 11:16:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-problems-frequently-found-by-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/5-problems-frequently-found-by-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Get a Home Inspection &amp; How I Can Help </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fu_mBvxCtjI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are buying a home, you need to have it inspected by a professional home inspector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’ll show you how you can get a free home inspection (including a radon test and sewer scope). First, I want to explain why it’s so important to get one in the first place. Brody Lotz, the co-owner of American Professional Home Inspection, is here to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why is an inspection so important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing is that when you buy a home, especially as a first-time buyer, you are making one of the biggest investments of your life. You want peace of mind. You don’t want to walk into a bad situation or money pit. Inspectors like Brody look at things to protect your investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What major components are covered in a home inspection?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important things inspectors look for are structural issues. “We check the roof for leaks and look at plumbing, electrical, and, of course, the foundation,” says Brody. “We really pay attention to big-ticket safety items. We also look at your appliances like the water heater and the furnace, which could be a big deal down the road.” Your inspector is there to make sure you are protected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is radon and why do you need to test for it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radon is present everywhere in the air, but it tends to accumulate in basements. Radon is a radioactive gas that dissipates in the air, but radon levels can rise in your home. If the house does have high levels of radon, it can be mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in my opinion, it’s also very important to check the sewer line. I’ve heard a lot of horror stories out there where someone buys a house, the sewer line collapses, and the basement is flooded with sewage. Not all homes need a sewer line inspection, though. According to Brody, he determines that on a case by case basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all depends on what kind of drain pipes there are, how old the home is, and if there are a lot of trees in the front yard. Those are all major concerns. If Brody can determine what the pipes are made out of, that can help determine whether or not the property needs a sewer line inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=HOME INSPECTIONS PROTECT YOUR INVESTMENT.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-get-home-inspection-how.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“HOME INSPECTIONS PROTECT YOUR INVESTMENT.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the sewer line collapses after you buy the house, that’s automatically a $10,000 to $15,000 fix. You can protect yourself from that by paying a much smaller amount for a home inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I have a home inspection certificate valued at $600. If you are the first buyer to contact me, I will pay for your inspection, as well as your radon and sewer line tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to go above and beyond that, so here’s my next offer: If you buy a house with me before the end of 2017, I will pay for your home inspection to make sure you are protected when making such a big investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 11:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-get-home-inspection-how.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-get-home-inspection-how.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Home Value</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colors That Make You Money</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vnc35lrGiiU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people have heard that you should stick with neutral colors when painting your home before a sale. However, a new study shows that this may no longer be the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your Colorado Springs home? Get a home value report
Buying a Colorado Springs Home? Click here for full MLS access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that you could add thousands to the value of your home by spending less than $100?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard that neutral paint colors are best for your home. However, a recent study from Money Magazine now indicates that you may want to go with something a little bolder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study included more than 32,000 photos of homes, and the results showed that certain colors in certain rooms can increase the value of your home by more than $5,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A NAVY BLUE FRONT DOOR CAN REALLY MAKE THE HOUSE POP.%20http://localhost:4000/colors-that-make-you-money.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A NAVY BLUE FRONT DOOR CAN REALLY MAKE THE HOUSE POP.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes with blue or gray-blue kitchens sold for about $1,800 more. A lot of white in a kitchen can also help it to appear cleaner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a smaller room like a bathroom, an accent wall is going to give you much more bang for your buck. Powder blue and periwinkle are very popular colors for bathrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes with bold shades of blue also tend to boost home value. Dining rooms look good in slate blue or pale gray, while living rooms generally benefit from a light beige or pale taupe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the exterior of the home, a navy blue front door can really make the house pop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not an interior decorator or a stager, but I am connected with a team of professionals who can help you sell your home for the most money with simple tips like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 10:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/colors-that-make-you-money.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/colors-that-make-you-money.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Reasons People Hire Me Over Other Agents</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nhbc8E9C78Y?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three reasons you should hire me to help you sell your home over all the other agents in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your Colorado Springs home? Get a home value report
Buying a Colorado Springs Home? Click here for full MLS access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to answer a question that I get asked a lot: “Jeff, there are 3,000 real estate agents in this town. Why should I pick you?” There are three answers I can provide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. I’m a highly experienced professional.&lt;/strong&gt; Everybody knows that the market is hot right now. When that happens, a lot of people get into real estate. The person that changed the tires on your car last month could be your Realtor tomorrow. The person you’re interviewing right now to handle your largest financial asset could also have a part-time job at Dillard’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to make sure the person you hire is a full-time, committed professional. I’ve been doing this for more than 15 years and have sold more than 1,000 homes. There are very few scenarios I haven’t seen. This is important because I can predict any issues in advance so we can eliminate them and make your transaction as smooth as possible. The market has changed a lot in those 15 years—it’s gone up, then down, and now it’s back up again. It’s changed, and so have I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=MY EXPERIENCE, MY TEAM’S FLEXIBILITY, AND THE COMPANY I WORK FOR WILL GET YOU THE RESULTS YOU’RE LOOKING FOR.%20http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-people-hire-me-over-other.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“MY EXPERIENCE, MY TEAM’S FLEXIBILITY, AND THE COMPANY I WORK FOR WILL GET YOU THE RESULTS YOU’RE LOOKING FOR.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. My common sense listing system.&lt;/strong&gt; A lot of Realtors put you in the same system but my team has got a lot of flexibility. We offer flexible commissions and the right to sell your house by yourself while it’s listed with me and pay nothing. After all the advertising we do and the buyers we bring to your house, you still have the option to fire me. I don’t think you’re going to do that though, and that’s because of reason No. 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The results we get.&lt;/strong&gt; The team I have and the company I work for will get you better results and provide you with better service, period. RE/MAX Properties is the No. 1 company in town. Since 1989, they’ve sold more homes than any other company. Right now, one out of every six houses in this city is listed with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are factors you should look for in any agent you hire, but my experience, my team’s flexibility, and the company I work for will get you the results you want. Whether you’re thinking about selling or buying a house, feel free to call me or send me an email. I’d be happy to assist you and get you the results you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 13:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-people-hire-me-over-other.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-reasons-people-hire-me-over-other.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare for a Successful Open House</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J7rPbpEsMSk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open houses are a tried and true method of selling a home, but you need to do it right to get buyers through the door. Here are a few tips to make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your Colorado Springs home? Get a home value report
Buying a Colorado Springs Home? Click here for full MLS access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open houses are one of the oldest ways to sell a house, and they can still be effective. They can really be hit and miss, so if you decide to have one, you need to make sure you do it right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by depersonalizing the house so that when buyers walk through, they can visualize themselves living there, not you. Remove anything polarizing, anything religious, and believe it or not, sports team-related things. Secondly, you need to declutter the house. You know you’ll be moving, so you can actually start to pre-pack, as I call it. You want to create space so buyers can really see the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to lure buyers into your home. The outside of the house can be more important because if buyers don’t get a good first impression from your home’s curb appeal, they might just keep on driving. Clean your walkway, get rid of spider webs, paint your front door, and make sure your lawn is mowed and inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=YOU WANT TO LURE BUYERS INTO YOUR HOME.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-successful-open-house.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“YOU WANT TO LURE BUYERS INTO YOUR HOME.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any leftover items on a honey-do list that have been there for a while, you want to take care of them now. Better yet, you can hire a handyman to do it. You don’t want buyers to see repairs you’ve put off as chores they’ll inherit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, hire a professional real estate agent to really get buyers through the door. You can do all the steps I’ve mentioned, but if you can’t get buyers into your house, it’s all for naught. An agent will cast a wide net to get buyers through your door and the highest offer possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about preparing for an open house or you’re considering selling your house, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to helping you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-successful-open-house.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-for-successful-open-house.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your Colorado Springs Listing Expired. Now What?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UtLXkZWitao?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens if you’re a seller in a hot market but your house fails to sell? That’s where we come in as experts in listings that expire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling your Colorado Springs home? Get a home value report
Buying a Colorado Springs Home? Click here for full MLS access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most markets in the country, the Colorado Springs market has been pretty hot for awhile now. Prices and sales are up, but inventory and interest rates remain low. Because of this, most homes on the market sell pretty quickly. What if your house wasn’t one of those? What if it became an expired listing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few small adjustments you can make to help you sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a home doesn’t sell, the homeowner usually does one of three things. They either re-list with the same agent to get the same results, or they may decide to either rent it or keep it. If your home won’t sell and it’s frustrating you, you need to bring me out to take a look at it. Many times, all it takes is a small adjustment to the approach of selling it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU’RE A SELLER IN A HOT MARKET BUT YOUR HOUSE FAILS TO SELL? THAT’S WHERE WE COME IN AS EXPERTS IN LISTINGS THAT EXPIRE.%20http://localhost:4000/your-colorado-springs-listing-expired.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU’RE A SELLER IN A HOT MARKET BUT YOUR HOUSE FAILS TO SELL? THAT’S WHERE WE COME IN AS EXPERTS IN LISTINGS THAT EXPIRE.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I specialize in helping homeowners sell homes that didn’t sell the first time. If you check out the video above, you can see some examples of houses that didn’t sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One sat on the market for 59 days with no offers. The photos of the home were a bit dark and made the rooms looks small. So, we came in with our professional photographer and also made some staging adjustments. The house, in turn, sold in four days for more than $2,000 above list price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the best markets, some homes just don’t sell. So let my team of experts take a look at it and help you go from a ‘shown’ to a ‘sold.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email soon. We look forward to helping you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 15:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/your-colorado-springs-listing-expired.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/your-colorado-springs-listing-expired.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Renovation Tips for Colorado Springs Home Sellers </title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fPliTbSZlqg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard me say many times that now is a great time to be in the real estate market. When most people want to maximize the money they get out of their home sale, they start renovating their property. However, there are a few pitfalls you should keep in mind before you renovate your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many homeowners, selling is something you may only do once or twice in your lifetime. I recommend consulting with the professionals if you are thinking about doing major changes to your house. If you are making those renovations for you and your family to enjoy, you don’t have to worry too much. If you are selling your home soon, though, definitely check in with a real estate professional before you do anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=TALK TO A REAL ESTATE PROFESSIONAL BEFORE YOU START RENOVATIONS.%20http://localhost:4000/3-renovation-tips-for-colorado-springs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“TALK TO A REAL ESTATE PROFESSIONAL BEFORE YOU START RENOVATIONS.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three main reasons why you should consult with a professional:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. New owners may not have the same taste as you.&lt;/strong&gt; Though there are a few clean-slate-type designs that may seem universally pleasing, you never know how a potential buyer might react. Aside from painting in neutral colors and modernizing kitchens and bathrooms, generally speaking, less is more when it comes to renovations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The value of your house may already be topped off.&lt;/strong&gt; Depending on the market you’re in, your home may already be at its maximum home value limit. If the value of your home is already significantly higher than other homes in your neighborhood, dumping money into renovations could be a huge waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. You will run into hidden costs while renovating.&lt;/strong&gt; The last thing you want to do is open a can of worms that will cost you a lot of money. You may run into issues hidden behind the walls. No matter your budget, most homeowners run into problems that end up costing a lot more money than they expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, I can help you figure out which home renovations will bring you the most return on investment. I can also put you in touch with great contractors, electricians, and more to help you with any updates you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-renovation-tips-for-colorado-springs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-renovation-tips-for-colorado-springs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Regrets of Colorado Springs Buyers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dCG3UYArILc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been keeping an eye on the Colorado Springs market lately, you know that now is a good time to buy. However, you may not know about some of the pitfalls you could become victim to. Today we are going to share with you some of our experience, by letting you know some of the most common regrets that home buyers come to us with. Hopefully after learning these, you won’t make the same mistakes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I wish I hadn’t financed every dollar the bank wanted to lend me”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because the bank will lend you $400,000 doesn’t mean you need to apply for that big of a loan. A good rule of thumb is to spend about 20% less than the bank will loan you, so a $320,000 loan, as opposed to a $400,000 loan, is a better option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Hopefully you won't make the same mistakes!%20http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-regrets-of-colorado-springs.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Hopefully you won’t make the same mistakes!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I wish I hadn’t used all my cash”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is pretty common, as a lot of buyers don’t realize all the costs that go into purchasing a home. Money for a down payment isn’t all the money you are going to need. You are also going to need closing costs, money for repairs, and money for upgrades. The point is, when you get your keys, you want to make sure you’re not out of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“I wish I didn’t spend so much time looking at short sales and foreclosures”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distressed properties aren’t the deals they once were. There are much fewer of them than there were in the past, and you can’t control the time frame with these. They might be slightly less expensive, but come with a lot more headaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid these and all the other common regrets that buyers make in Colorado Springs, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 13:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-regrets-of-colorado-springs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-regrets-of-colorado-springs.html</guid>
        
        <category>Colorado Springs Real Estate Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
